Alastair Low



Online Portfolio: http://alastairlow.co.uk
Personal Games: http://lowtek.co.uk

Personal Games: http://lowtek.co.uk

12 Cleghorn Street flat 3R, Dundee DD2 2NR

DOB: 20/04/1991 Mob: 0790 606 96 20 email: lowtek@hotmail.co.uk

About Me:

I am a games Artist/Designer. I specialise in non-photorealistic styles. I have been making games since I was in primary school and continue to work on hobby games whenever I'm not playing games. I am one of 3 Directors at Dundee MakerSpace.

Skills:

I am a good problem solver who is punctual and motivated. I like to learn and am good at working in groups, working to deadlines and working on my own.

Intermediate	Competent	Experienced (10 years +)
Graphics Gale	Flash	Blender 3D (13 years+)
zbrush	Maya	Photoshop (10 years+)
Gimp	3dsMax	
Dreamweaver	Illustrator	
Krita	Final Cut Pro	
	Adobe Premier Pro	
	Adobe After effects	
	Unity 3D	
	Sign Lab	

Shipped Games:

SAS 4 Zombie Assault
Bloons Super Monkey 2
Bloons Monkey City
Bloons Adventure Time TD

Upcoming Games

A Familiar Fairy Tale: Dyslexic text Based Adventure Game. (Early Access)

Relevant Experience:

Ninja Kiwi: July 2013 – Present

Artist - Work in small teams to make 2d and 3d artwork for mobile games. Helping create pipelines.

Alastair Low CV 2018 - 2019 Mobile: 790 606 96 20 email: lowtek@hotmail.co.uk

Dundee MakerSpace: 2017 - Present

Director – Help organise our local community non-profit makerspace. Performing inductions on 3d printers, laser cutter and other tools. Making marketing materials and logos.

Dsigns: May 2008 – 2013 (Contract Work)

Worked in a small sign making workshop where I designed and manufactured several types of signs for shops business. Worked in illustrator and Sian Lab and learned how to work to client briefs.

Dare+:

Took part in Dare+ in summer 2012, worked on Anton's Adventure (2D adventure game for mobile)

Scouts:

Part of a patrol that came 4th in the inter area camping competition and as a Patrol Leader of a successful patrol for some time. I learned how to take orders and improved my problem solving.

Education:

BA (Hons) Computer Arts (First) University of Abertay Dundee

Honours project:

The aim was to emulating traditional 2D styles in a real-time 3DGame engine. This involved exploring a variety of different methods to achieve a range of non-photorealistic art styles. A 5 level game was the final outcome. Blender game engine was used as it allowed me to prototype without coding.)

HND Computer Art (A) Central College Glasgow

Awards:

College: Best student of the year award

Ludum Dare 25: 2nd place for the Graphics category. (Game: You are the Dragon)

Creative Loop Award: Best interactive media Artefact.

Interests:

I like Playing and Creating Video Games. I enter game jams and speed modelling contests as much as I can either in teams or on my own. I like to collect things such as old consoles, games, toys, Pop-Up books and various weird musical instruments. I also like watching movies and making short films as well as video blogs and tutorials.

References:

Dsigns:

Elsi Duncan D Signs Limited 41 John Player Building Kerse road, Stirling FK7 7RP

Tel: 01786 470305

email: signs@dsigns.co.uk

Kenneth Fee:

Kenneth Fee Mprof Program Tutor University of Abertay Dundee Kydd Building Bell Street, Dundee DD1 1HG

Tel: 01382 308000

e-mail: K.Fee@live.abertay.ac.uk

Alastair Low CV 2018 - 2019 Mobile: 790 606 96 20 email: lowtek@hotmail.co.uk